Register of the Sidney D. Drell papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sidney D. Drell papers
1945-2015
80074
Hoover Institution Archives
27 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize folder (11.4 linear feet)
Speeches and writings, notes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, and printed matter relating to scientific and technological aspects of United States national security and intelligence issues, including nuclear weapons, nuclear stockpile management, satellite reconnaissance, biological and chemical warfare issues, and terrorism issues. Also includes material relating to the dissident Soviet physicist Andreĭ Sakharov, and to efforts on his behalf by Western scientists. Includes writings and letters by Sakharov.
Drell, Sidney D. (Sidney David), 1926-2016.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980, with increments received in 1981 and 2016.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Sidney D. Drell papers, Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (SLAC) Archives and History Office
Scientists for Sakharov, Orlov, and Shcharansky records, Hoover Institution Archives
Paul J. Flory papers, Hoover Institution Archives
William Shockley miscellaneous papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1926 Born, Atlantic City, New Jersey
1946 A.B. in Physics, Princeton University
1947 M.A. in Physics, University of Illinois
1949 Ph.D. in Physics, University of Illinois
1966 Member, President's Science Advisory Committee
1969 Elected to the National Academy of Sciences
1969-1981 Consultant, U.S. Arms Control and Disarmament Agency
1969-1986 Executive Head, Theoretical Physics, Stanford Linear Accelerator Center
1974 First met Andrei Sakharov in Moscow
1977 Accepted the Joseph Human Rights Award for Sakharov
1977-1990 Member, American Committee on U.S.-Soviet Relations (formerly Committee on East-West Accord)
1980 Advisory Board, Andrei Sakharov Defense Campaign
1981 Chairman, International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov
1983-1989 Founding Co-Director, Stanford's Center for International Security and Arms Control
1984 Prize Fellowship of the John D. and Catherine T. MacArthur Foundation
1986 President, American Physical Society
1989-1996 Adjunct Professor, Department of Engineering and Public Policy, Carnegie Mellon University
1990-1991 Chairman, House Armed Services Committee Panel on Nuclear Weapons Safety
1992-2001 Member, President’s Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board
1995 Chair, JASON Study for Department of Energy on Nuclear Testings
1998 Retired as deputy director from Stanford Linear Accelerator Center
1998-2016 Senior Fellow, Hoover Institution
2000 Received Enrico Fermi Award
2006 With George Shultz, initiated a program at the Hoover Institution to develop practical steps towards achieving a world without nuclear weapons
2013 Awarded National Medal of Honor
2016 Died
Source: http://www.hoover.org/profiles/sidney-d-drell
Scope and Content of Collection
The Sidney D. Drell papers include speeches and writings, notes, correspondence, memoranda, reports, studies, and printed matter related to scientific and technological aspects of United States national security and intelligence issues, including nuclear weapons, nuclear stockpile management, satellite reconnaissance, biological and chemical warfare issues, and terrorism issues. In addition, the papers include material related to the dissident Soviet physicist Andrei Sakharov, and to efforts on his behalf by Western scientists.
These latter records document Drell's efforts to aid Andrei Sakharov during Sakharov's arrest and exile, as well as his personal relationship with Sakharov and Elena (Yelena) Bonner. The Andrei Sakharov Chronological File includes correspondence with Sakharov and family members such as Elena Bonner, Tat'iana Yankelevich (Bonner's daughter and Sakharov's step-daughter), and Tat'iana's husband Efrem Yankelevich. Letters to scientists and members of various organizations document Drell's efforts to arrange petitions, plan conferences, and disseminate information about Sakharov's work and exile in Gor'kii (Gorky). The series includes open letters between Drell and Sakharov discussing topics such as Sakharov's arrest and arms control. Also included are writings and typescripts by Drell and Sakharov. Material concerning the Andrei Sakharov Institute can also be found in this series.
In 1981, Drell was the chairman of the International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov, a birthday tribute to Sakharov designed to recognize his scientific contributions as well as express support for him. The Andrei Sakharov Collected Materials and Andrei Sakharov Chronological File contain correspondence and conference materials related to this event.
The Speeches and Writings series includes typescripts, manuscripts, and clippings written by Drell and Sakharov. Writings by Sakharov include physics papers (with typescripts in Russian), interviews with Sakharov, articles describing Sakharov's views on human rights, and descriptions of his experience in exile. For more writings by Drell, see also Incremental Speeches and Writings.
In addition to his work as a physicist, Drell was an arms control specialist. He advised the United States government on technical national security and defense issues and consulted for Los Alamos National Laboratory and Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory. He served on various advisory committees, including the President’s Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board. The Advisory Work File documents Drell’s consulting work through his research files, correspondence, and writings. Included are documents concerning the Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty and the Stockpile Stewardship Program.
Drell was a founding member of JASON, an independent group of scientists formed to advise the United States government. The JASON File includes documentation related to meetings, such as the annual summer study, as well as many reports for which Drell served as chair, study leader, or a contributor. Topics of reports include stockpile stewardship, nuclear testing, tritium, subcritical experiments, lasers, and stockpile aging. Although most reports are in their final form, these materials include some drafts and notes.
The collection includes Printed Matter related to topics such as Sakharov, nuclear weapons, and intelligence, as well as histories compiled by the National Reconnaissance Office.
Finally, the Audiovisual Material series contains sound recordings of the conference "Implications of the Reykjavik Summit on Its Twentieth Anniversary," as well as a photograph, and a videorecording about Sakharov.
Nuclear weapons.; Biological warfare.; Chemical warfare.; Terrorism.; Intelligence service--United States.; United States--Defenses.; Physics.; Science--United States.; Dissenters--Soviet Union.; Sakharov, Andreĭ, 1921-1989.; Civil rights--Soviet Union.; Scientists--Soviet Union.
- Andrei Sakharov Chronological File, 1968-1992 (Boxes 1-3)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes correspondence, writings, typescripts, and clippings, arranged chronologically. Retains many of Drell's original folder labels (folders labeled by year) and his original order.
  - Articles about Sakharov, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - 1974-1976 (Box-folder 1: 2)
  - 1977 (Box-folder 1: 3)
  - 1978 (Box-folder 1: 4)
  - Article by Sakharov, "Nuclear Energy and the Freedom of the West,", 1978 June (Box-folder 1: 5)
  - 1979 (Box-folder 1: 6)
  - 1980 (Box-folder 1: 7)
  - 1980-1982 (Box-folder 1: 8)
  - 1981 (Box-folder 1: 9)
  - Open letter from Sakharov to Drell, 1981 January 31 (Box-folder 1: 10)
  - Letter from Sakharov to Drell, 1981 June (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Article by Sakharov, "The Social Responsibility of Scientists,", 1981 June 1 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 1982 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - 1983 (Box-folder 1: 14)
  - Open letter from Sakharov to Drell, "The Danger of Thermonuclear War,", 1983 February 2 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - Drell's reply to Sakharov's February 2, 1983 open letter, 1983 September 20 (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1984 (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 1985 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 1986 (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - Elena Bonner, 1986 (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - Congressional Record regarding Sakharov's 65th birthday, 1986 May 21 (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - 1987 (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Sakharov and Bonner commencement addresses, 1987 June 14 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Sakharov book chapters with English translations, 1987-1988, undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - 1988 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Edward Teller, 1988 November 11 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    Includes speech by Sakharov.
  - 1989 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - 1990-1992 (Box-folder 3: 3)
- Andrei Sakharov Collected Materials, 1966-2000 (Boxes 3-6)
  Includes clippings, conference materials, correspondence, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject or format.
  - General, 1980, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 4-5)
  - Andrei Sakharov Institute
    - 1966-1967, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - 1984-1985 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Tribute to Sakharov, Carnegie Hall, 1984 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Biographical material
    - General, circa 1986 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Autobiographical note, 1981 (Box-folder 3: 10)
  - Bonner, Elena, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 3: 11-12)
  - Clippings
    - Undated (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - 1970-1975 (Box-folder 3: 14)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - Conference on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE), 1980-1981 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - Correspondence
    - General, 1968-1986 (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Sakharov, Andrei and Elena Bonner, 1978-1983, undated (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - "Humanity in the Universe" poster (New York Academy of Sciences Symposium), undated (Map case)
  - Human rights (Sakharov and Orlov), 1983 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - Hunger strike, 1981 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov (May 1-2, 1981), 1968, 1980-1981, undated (Box-folder 5: 1-7)
  - Joseph Prize for Human Rights, 1977 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Khronika Press Information Bulletins, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Memorial and death
    - General, 1981-1990 (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - International Andrei Sakharov Memorial Congress, 1991 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - National Academy of Sciences (NAS), 1980-1985 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Photographs, Drell and Sakharov, 1989 August (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Physics Today Sakharov issue (August 1990)
    - Printed matter, 1990 (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Eisenhower, Susan and Sagdeev, Roald, "Sakharov in His Own Words,", 1990 (Box-folder 6: 5)
    - Fainberg, Vladimir, "Precursor of Perestroika,", 1990 (Box-folder 6: 6)
    - Gol'danskiĭ, Vitalii, "Scientist, Thinker, Humanist,", 1990 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Protests and statements of support, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Reports and lectures, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Scientists for Orlov and Shcharansky (SOS), 1979 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Stanford Daily and Stanford University Campus Report, 1984 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Testimony, 1980 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Miscellany, 1969-1990, undated (Box-folder 6: 13)
- Speeches and Writings, 1966-2000 (Boxes 6-7)
  Includes typescripts, manuscripts, clippings, and interviews, arranged into two groups, Drell and Sakharov, then chronologically thereunder.
  - Drell
    - Travelogue, 1976 (Box-folder 6: 14)
    - "Panel on U.S.-Soviet Relations in a World Perspective," The Dickinson Symposia, Stanford University, 1976 May 27 (Box-folder 6: 15)
    - "Introductory Remarks for Special Symposium to Honor Andrei Sakharov,", 1981 January 26 (Box-folder 6: 16)
    - "Basing the MX Missile: A Better Idea,", 1981 May/June (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - "Opening Remarks at the International Conference in Honor of Andrei Sakharov,", 1981 May 1-2 (Box-folder 6: 18)
    - "News Media Coverage of Nuclear Weapons," keynote address to Conference on War, Peace, and the News Media, 1983 March 18 (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - "On Sakharov, Human Rights, and Arms Control,", 1983 September/October (Box-folder 6: 20)
    - "Statement on Andrei Sakharov to the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe,", 1984 May 22 (Box-folder 6: 21)
    - "Remarks at Dinner for Yelena Bonner,", 1986 February 11 (Box-folder 6: 22)
    - "Andrei Dmitrievich Sakharov, 1921-1989,", circa 1989 (Box-folder 6: 23)
    - "Andrei Sakharov and the Nuclear Danger,", 2000 May (Box-folder 6: 24)
  - Sakharov
    - "The Initial Stage of an Expanding Universe and the Appearance of a Nonuniform Distribution of Matter,", 1966 January (Box-folder 6: 25)
    - "Maximum Temperature of Thermal Radiation" (1966 June), 1966, undated (Box-folder 6: 26-27)
    - Book review, The Sakharov Manifesto, reviewed by Marshall Shulman, 1968 November (Box-folder 6: 28)
    - "A Letter from Dr. Sakharov,", 1970 April 13 (Box-folder 6: 29)
    - Interview of Sakharov, "Dissent in the Soviet Union,", 1973 (Box-folder 6: 30)
    - "How I Came to Dissent,", 1974 March 21 (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - "Tomorrow: The View From Red Square,", 1974 August 24 (Box-folder 7: 2)
    - "Spectral Density of Eigenvalues of the Wave Equation and Vacuum Polarization,", 1975 (Box-folder 7: 3)
    - "Soviet Physicist Urges 'Full' Disarming,", 1975 October 27 (Box-folder 7: 4)
    - "The Need for an Open World,", 1975 November (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Interview of Sakharov by Coleman, "Sakharov on Human Rights,", 1977 March 14 (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - "The Baryonic Asymmetry of the Universe,", 1979 April (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - "World Security, Human Rights Linked,", circa 1980 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Sakharov quote from the New York Times, 1980 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - "Mass Formula for Mesons and Baryons" (1980 April) (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - "Estimate of the Quark-Gluon Coupling Constant,", 1980 May (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - "Sakharov: A Letter from Exile,", 1980 June 8 (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - "Observations in Exile: Sakharov Sends a Letter to the West,", 1980 June 13 (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - "Sakharov's Statement Carried from Gorky to Moscow by His Wife,", 1980 June 27 (Box-folder 7: 14)
    - "Cosmological Models of the Universe with Rotation of Time's Arrow" (1980 July), 1980, undated (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - "An Open Letter to the President of the Soviet Academy of Sciences, A. P. Aleksandrov,", 1980 October 20 (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - "Statement for Press and Radio,", 1981 (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - Open letter to Drell, 1981 January (Box-folder 7: 18)
    - "A Letter from Sakharov in Exile,", 1981 April 22 (Box-folder 7: 19)
    - "The Responsibility of Scientists" (1981 June 25) (Box-folder 7: 20)
    - "An Appeal,", 1981 August 16 (Box-folder 7: 21)
    - "The Danger of Thermonuclear War,", 1983 (Box-folder 7: 22)
    - "Multisheeted Models of the Universe" (1983 February), 1982-1983 (Box-folder 7: 23)
    - "Andrei Sakharov from Exile," International League for Human Rights, 1983 October (Box-folder 7: 24)
    - "Cosmological Transitions with a Change in Metric Signature" (1984 May), 1984, undated (Box-folder 7: 25)
    - "Andrei Sakharov's Appeal on Beginning His Hunger Strike," Khronika Press Information Bulletin, 1984 May (Box-folder 7: 26)
    - "My KGB Ordeal,", 1986 February 24 (Box-folder 7: 27)
    - "Commencement Addresses," The College of Staten Island, 1987 June 14 (Box-folder 7: 28)
      Includes speech by Elena Bonner.
    - Interview of Andrei Sakharov and Elena Bonner by Mark Levin, 1988 (Box-folder 7: 29)
    - "Remarks of Dr. Andrei Sakharov for the Seventh Annual Ethics and Public Policy Dinner Honoring Dr. Edward Teller,", 1988 November 16 (Box-folder 7: 30)
- Incremental Speeches and Writings, 1960-2012, undated (Boxes 8-9)
  Includes typescripts, printed matter, notes, and correspondence, arranged chronologically.
  - "The Running Coupling Constant in Quantum Electrodynamics,", undated (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - "Infrared Radiation from the Atmosphere," with Malvin A. Ruderman, Institute for Defense Analysis, JASON Division, 1960 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - "Radio Propagation Through Artificially Enhanced Scattering,", 1956, 1981 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Relativistic Quantum Mechanics, with James D. Bjorken, Russian translation, 1978 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - "SALT and Beyond," Common Sense in U.S.-Soviet Relations, 1978 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - "Experimental Status of Quantum Electrodynamics,", 1979 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - "Anomalous Magnetic Moment and Limits on Fermion Substructure,", 1980 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - "Arms Control: Is There Still Hope?," Daedalus, 1980 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - "The Moral Issue and Deterrence," Societal Issues, 1987 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Sakharov Remembered, edited by Drell and Sergei P. Kapitza, 1991 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Notes on Compton back-scattering, 1992 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - "Theoretical Aspects of Lepton-Hadron Scattering,", 1992 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - "Technical Issues of a Nuclear Test Ban,", 1994 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - "Reminiscences of Work on National Reconnaissance," Recollections of the Pioneers and Founders of National Reconnaissance, 2002 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - "A Safer Nuclear Enterprise,", 2012 (Box-folder 9: 4)
- Advisory Work File, 1945-2014 (Boxes 9-19)
  Includes correspondence, writings, research files, and printed matter related to Drell's advisory work for the United States government and private organizations, arranged alphabetically, mainly in two groups: organizations file and subject file.
  - Organizations file
    - Argonne National Laboratory, non-proliferation, 2004 (Box-folder 9: 5)
    - Charlie Allen Task Force, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 9: 6-7)
    - Director of Central Intelligence
      - Emerging missile threat, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 9: 8)
      - Small Satellite Review Panel, 1996 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Intelligence Technology Innovation Center
      - Murder Board, 2001-2002 (Box-folder 9: 10-12)
      - Murder Board, Warren Rudman, George Tenet, 2002 (Box-folder 9: 13)
    - Los Alamos National Laboratory
      - Pit Manufacturing/Certification Oversight Committee, 2001 (Box-folder 9: 14)
      - Senior Advisory Group, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 9: 15)
    - Los Alamos National Security and Lawrence Livermore National Security
      - Large Bore Power Gun Review Committee, 2010 (Box-folder 9: 16)
      - Mission Committee, 2006-2014 (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
    - National Nuclear Security Administration Advisory Panel, 2002-2004 (Box-folder 10: 3)
    - President's Council on National Laboratories, 2007 (Box-folder 10: 4)
    - President's Foreign Intelligence Advisory Board
      - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 10: 5)
      - 1997-2002 (Box-folder 10: 6)
      - Non-proliferation, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 11: 1-2)
    - Princeton University, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 11: 3-4)
    - Senate Select Committee on Intelligence, 1989-1992 (Box-folder 11: 5-6)
    - University of California, Office of the President, 2004-2009 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Subject file
    - Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty
      - 1995-1997, 2006 (Box-folder 12: 1-3)
      - 1995-2002 (Box-folder 12: 4-5)
      - 1995-2002 (Box-folder 13: 1)
      - 1999-2001 (Box-folder 13: 2-4)
      - Stockpile Stewardship Program, 1994-2000 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
      - Stockpile Stewardship Program (cont'd.), 1994-2000 (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
      - Stockpile Stewardship Program and national security, 1998-2001 (Box-folder 14: 4-6)
      - Stockpile Stewardship Program and national security (cont'd.), 1998-2001 (Box-folder 15: 1-5)
    - Concerns about Department of Energy Science, 2000 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - Corona Satellite Program, 1966, 1995-2002, undated (Box-folder 16: 2-5)
    - Discriminate force, 2000-2002 (Box-folder 17: 1-4)
    - Hart-Rudman Commission, 1945, 2001 (Box-folder 17: 5-6)
    - National Ignition Facility, 1997 (Box-folder 18: 1)
    - National Reconnaissance Office, 1963, 2000 (Box-folder 18: 2)
    - Propellant Hazard Test and Analysis Program, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 18: 3)
    - Red Team, 2010 (Box-folder 18: 4)
    - Shalikashvili, John, 1997-2001 (Box-folder 18: 5-7)
    - Shalikashvili, John and Los Alamos National Laboratory, 2000 (Box-folder 19: 1)
    - Subcritical experiments, 1998 (Box-folder 19: 2)
    - Terrorism and homeland security, 1996-2002 (Box-folder 19: 3-5)
    - Tritium, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 19: 6)
  - Writings by others, 1972-2006 (Box-folder 19: 7)
- JASON File, 1988-2015 (Boxes 20-25)
  Includes correspondence, reports, notes, and meeting materials related to Drell's advisory work with JASON, arranged alphabetically by format.
  - Administrative file, 2001-2013 (Box-folder 20: 1-2)
  - Meetings
    - Summer study, hydronuclear testing, 1995 (Box-folder 20: 3-4)
    - Fall meeting, 2004 (Box-folder 20: 5)
    - Summer study, 2005 (Box-folder 20: 6-7)
    - Winter study, 2005 (Box-folder 21: 1)
    - Summer study, 2006 (Box-folder 21: 2-3)
    - Spring meeting, 2007 (Box-folder 21: 4)
    - Fall meeting, 2008 (Box-folder 21: 5)
    - Summer study, 2009 (Box-folder 21: 6)
    - Fall meeting, 2010 (Box-folder 21: 7)
    - Spring meeting, 2012 (Box-folder 21: 8)
    - Summer study, 2012 (Box-folder 21: 9)
  - Notes, 1995 (Box-folder 21: 10)
  - Reports
    - 1988 (Box-folder 21: 11)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 21: 12)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 21: 13)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 21: 14)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 22: 1-2)
    - 1995 (Box-folder 22: 3-4)
    - 1996 (Box-folder 22: 5-6)
    - 1997 (Box-folder 22: 7)
    - 1998 (Box-folder 23: 1)
    - 1999 (Box-folder 23: 2)
    - 2000 (Box-folder 23: 3)
    - 2001 (Box-folder 23: 4)
    - 2002 (Box-folder 23: 5)
    - 2003 (Box-folder 23: 6-7)
    - 2005 (Box-folder 23: 8)
    - 2006 (Box-folder 23: 9)
    - 2007 (Box-folder 23: 10)
    - 2008 (Box-folder 24: 1)
    - 2011 (Box-folder 24: 2)
    - 2012 (Box-folder 24: 3)
    - 2014 (Box-folder 24: 4)
    - 2015 (Box-folder 24: 5)
  - Subject file
    - Dismantlement study, undated (Box-folder 24: 6)
    - Nuclear testing review and inertial confinement fusion, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 24: 7-8)
    - Nuclear testing review and inertial confinement fusion (cont'd.), 1995-1996 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Subcritical experiments, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 25: 2)
- Printed Matter, 1969-2001, undated (Boxes 25-26)
  Scope and contents note
  Includes monographs and booklets related to Andrei Sakharov, nuclear weapons, and intelligence, as well as histories compiled by the National Reconnaissance Office.
  - General
    - Undated (Box-folder 25: 3)
    - 1990s (Box-folder 25: 4-6)
    - 2000s (Box-folder 26: 1-2)
  - National Reconnaissance Office histories, 1969-2001, undated (Box-folder 26: 3-5)
- Audiovisual Material, 2006-2008, undated (Box 27)
  Includes compact discs, a photograph, and a VHS videocassette, arranged alphabetically by format.
  - Compact discs, conference, "Implications of the Reykjavik Summit on Its Twentieth Anniversary,", 2006 (Box-folder 27: 1)
  - Group photograph, Great Britain, 2008 (Box-folder 27: 2)
  - VHS videocassette, "Sakharov, HBO Cable Movie,", undated (Box-folder 27: 3)